Adeeb Musthafa V P

Software Developer

Mobile: +971 563864703

Email: adeebmustafa.vp@gmail.com

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/adeeb-musthafa-vp/

Dubai, UAE



PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Enthusiastic Senior Software Engineer with 2.5+ years in .NET Full Stack Development. Motivated to learn, grow and excel in the Software Industry. Currently working in product-based company Siemens Technology for the product PUD. Looking to leverage and grow as a Full Stack Developer.

SKILLS SUMMARY

- Programming Languages: C# , JavaScript
- Server Side Frameworks: ASP.NET, .NET MVC , MS SQL , Web API , Entity Framework , ADO.NET , REST API , XUnit
- Client Side: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery
- Tools: Visual Studio 2019, GitHub, TFS, SQLite Studio, Postman, SonarQube
- Soft Skills: Leadership, Event Management, Independent Contributor, Team Player

EXPERIENCE

Siemens Technology, Bangalore

Software Engineer (Full-time): Project - PUD Manager

July 2023 - Oct 2024

- APIs for PUD Manager: Created 15+ End-to-End APIs for CRUD operations in .NET MVC Framework for PUD Application.
- User Management: Implemented the concept of user management for the whole application with session management.
- Notification System: Created automatic pop-up notification system to inform users if any modification related to session is done.
- Frontend & Backend debugging skills: Worked on both frontend and backend simultaneously for application development and bug fixing.
- Custom Sticky Notes and page responsiveness: Worked on sticky notes development on UI and made responsive web pages.
- Product Innovation: Suggested brainstorming innovative ideas such as multiselect dropdown, listbox and sticky notes implementation.
- Collaboration and Team Building: Participated in Requirement Analysis, Code Reviews, Pair Programming.

Graduate Trainee Engineer (Full-time): Project - PUD Manager

Feb 2022 - June 2023

- APIs for PUD Manager: Created 5+ End-to-End APIs for CRUD operations in .NET MVC Framework for PUD Application.
- Performance Tuning: Reduced page load time by 80% by introducing bundling and minification, also optimized the existing jQuery code.
- Frontend & Backend debugging skills: Worked on both frontend and backend simultaneously for application development and bug fixing.
- Testing: Helped the testing team by being deeply involved in testing the application manually like Regression Test, Smoke Test and Integrated Test.

Luminar Technolab, Cochin

Data Science Intern (Internship)

Sep 2021 - Feb 2022

- Implemented advanced data analytics techniques and statistical models to uncover key business insights increased marketing ROI by 25% and optimized customer segmentation strategies, driving a 50% increase in overall sales in products.
- Mastered Big Data Analytics by working with Hadoop, Spark, Hive and ML algorithms; analyzed data sets to uncover trends, optimizing
 marketing strategy to boost customer acquisition by 20% and reducing churn by 45%.

EDUCATION

Aarupadai Veedu Institute Of Technology, Chennai

Aug 2017 - July 2021

Bachelor of Technology - Computer Science; GPA: 8.0

HONORS AND AWARDS

- Awarded twice STAR Performer at Siemens Technology June 2023 and January 2024.
- Promoted to Software Developer within a year for exceptional performance, staying highly motivated and confident.

CERTIFICATIONS

- Generative Al: Introduction to Large Language Models Linkedin
- GitHub Copilot First Look Linkedin
- What Is Generative AI Linkedin
- Data Science NACTECT Certification Luminar Technolab